<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>DAVEWALK.NET</title>
		<description>The website of software developer Dave Walk</description>		
		<link>http://davewalk.net</link>
		<atom:link href="http://davewalk.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Famo.us</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Perhaps you&amp;#39;ve heard of &lt;a href=&quot;http://famo.us&quot;&gt;Famo.us&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;#39;re a start-up that is developing a super slick rendering engine that can do crazy stuff like the demo on their homepage.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;#39;ve been gathering hype and (and a lot of VC funding) for a while now without a product that developers could use. Their website opens with a form to sign-up for a beta release and there have been some events for the lucky ones in San Francisco. But recently they sent out an email titled &amp;quot;FINALLY&amp;quot; that details the beginning of a public beta rollout on April 9th.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This section of the email was very interesting to me:   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Based on our experience with Hack Reactor students and private beta participants, this timeline is typical:   

&lt;p&gt;30 minutes: You complete the intro lessons in Famo.us University.&lt;/p&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;Hour 2: You build your first app example with physics animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hour 3: You can learn new techniques by reading Famo.us source code for any of the 40 example app interfaces in our gallery. You can also easily read and understand the reference documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then until sunrise: You look through the examples to get inspired. You work all night to build your first app, and it’s awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 week: You can build any of the animation example demos, you’ve mastered the concepts of Famo.us, and you’ve submitted some animation demos of your own to the community gallery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 weeks: You feel empowered to begin your own project in earnest with hopes of building an award-winning app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 month: You never look back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of releasing a rough version of their software, they&amp;#39;ve worked on developer evangelism ahead of time. And through this work they&amp;#39;ve realized and acknowledged that there is a learning curve to their engine and spinned it into a positive. In some fields a challenge can be seen as a feature of a product and not a downside of it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chances are good I&amp;#39;ll give Famo.us a shot next month. Game on!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 17:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2014/03/29/famous.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2014/03/29/famous.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Belief, or Why the Chicago Bulls Matter</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone that knows me knows that I&amp;#39;m a huge NBA fan. You probably aren&amp;#39;t, but stick with me on this one. It makes sense.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chicago Bulls have been a successful team for a few years now. One reason is they are led by a hometown point guard named Derrick Rose. Although Rose was only 20 when he played his first NBA game for the Bulls, he quickly became their leader. His demeanor set a tone for the team; he&amp;#39;s a super serious guy that doesn&amp;#39;t smile or joke around a lot. He&amp;#39;s known for reckless abandon on the court and putting his body on the line.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this isn&amp;#39;t really a story about Derrick Rose, because in April 2012 he tore the ACL in his left knee and didn&amp;#39;t play the entire 2012-2013 season. To most NBA fans when the star player goes down that team&amp;#39;s year is pretty much over. But not for the Bulls, who shocked Brooklyn Nets, a team with a big payroll and big expectations that year in the playoffs. Their &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nate_Robinson&quot;&gt;starting point guard at the time&lt;/a&gt; was 5&amp;#39;9&amp;quot;, a living example of adversity if there ever was one (fun fact: I&amp;#39;m an inch taller than a guy that plays in the NBA).  Plagued by injuries, they never stopped trying and they won a series that they had no reason to.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This season Rose got hurt &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;, leading to a second straight lost year. Then the team traded their anchor and possibly their best player, Luol Deng. Now at this point do you think the team just felt bad about themselves and folded?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bulls, man. The Bulls. No one fights like Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Zach Lowe (@ZachLowe_NBA) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ZachLowe_NBA/statuses/442746662071840769&quot;&gt;March 9, 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I try to catch the Bulls on TV whenever I can because afterwards I&amp;#39;ll feel fired up and want to go do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;. If I&amp;#39;m on a treadmill watching a game I&amp;#39;ll definitely be running a few extra miles. The Bulls push, they fight, they don&amp;#39;t give up. They beat the other team not because they have a great gameplan or have the most talent, but because they&amp;#39;re willing to go farther and sacrifice more. &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/DmkeohReH4U?t=1m29s&quot;&gt;Plays like this&lt;/a&gt; from last night&amp;#39;s win against a top team don&amp;#39;t happen in every NBA game.  Sure, they&amp;#39;re millionaires but they play against a bunch of other millionaires that they routinely out-hustle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Belief. Belief in what you&amp;#39;re working towards and your teammates no matter what adversity comes your way.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believing in a goal like the Bulls is something I&amp;#39;m trying to work towards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 08:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2014/03/25/belief-or-why-the-chicago-bulls-matter.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2014/03/25/belief-or-why-the-chicago-bulls-matter.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Website</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new davewalk.net! This website could be considered version 3.0 of this tiny little place for myself on the Internet. Version 1 was a Drupal website (horrible idea although I learned some valuable lessons). Version 2 was a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rigoneri/syte&quot;&gt;Syte&lt;/a&gt; (still viewable, for now, &lt;a href=&quot;http://davewalk.herokuapp.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) website that while being an awesome idea, didn&amp;#39;t really work for me because of slow page loads due to API calls to the Tumblr and search engine issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;#39;re looking at now is a static &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; website hosted on GitHub Pages which I believe will make it super simple to keep this website up-to-date. Blog posts are markdown files that I can write and preview in Sublime Text. I can create &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davewalk/davewalk.net/issues&quot;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt; to remind myself of blog post ideas. And each blog post has a link at the bottom to the actual markdown file in the GitHub repo in case a reader wants to correct me on something. Yes, I agree that this probably won&amp;#39;t be done very often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s still more to do too; I have to create a projects page to showcase the things I&amp;#39;ve worked on recently and a dedicated blog posts page with tags. I&amp;#39;m also going to make more of an effort to write new blog posts more often so check back soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2014 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2014/03/23/new-website.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2014/03/23/new-website.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Philly Hoods</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Today I’m releasing &lt;a href=&quot;http://phillyhoods.net/&quot;&gt;Philly Hoods&lt;/a&gt;, a
neighborhoods API for Philadelphia. For now it’s pretty simple: give it
a pair of coordinates in Philadelphia and it’ll tell you what
neighborhood you’re in and give you a GeoJSON representation of the
neighborhood polygon. Or, pass a string and it’ll try to match one or
more neighborhoods to it. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://phillyhoods.net/&quot;&gt;the docs&lt;/a&gt;
for more information and a demo. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davewalk/philly-hoods&quot;&gt;The code’s on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a simple project but it was fun to do and like all my side projects
it gave me a chance to mess around with some new technology for the
first time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Node.js&lt;/strong&gt;: This is my first project in production using Node. I’ve been
messing with it for a while on some larger things (some still in the
works) but it’s good to get something out the door. Again, I’m not
really doing anything crazy here, I’m using callbacks, I haven’t yet
gotten into the promises and all of the more advanced stuff. But I think
Node is ideal for writing APIs and will continue to look to it in the
future for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go with &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcavage.me/node-restify/&quot;&gt;Restify&lt;/a&gt; over
Express for writing the API and I’m really glad I did. It’s designed
specifically from writing RESTful APIs so it does a lot of the work for
you or makes other things easy with built-in Bunyan support for logging,
throttling and a few other small things that were helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PostgreSQL and PostGIS&lt;/strong&gt;: This is one that I’ve been wanting to dig into
for some time. It’s a database that I’ve messed with but never had to
work with from front to end on a project. It took me a while to figure
out to convert and insert the polygons into a table from a shapefile but
eventually I got it. Once you get the hang of the spatial queries that
you can do with PostGIS you realize that the possibilities are pretty
much endless. It’s kind of addictive. Definitely be using PostGIS again
in the future if a need something spatial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenShift&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ve used Heroku as a PaaS before, but never
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openshift.com/&quot;&gt;OpenShift&lt;/a&gt;. I think the two of them are
pretty similar from a workflow point of view (deploying from a
&lt;code&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;, what a beautiful thing). What I liked about OpenShift is
that you can actually SSH in to your gear (like a dyno) to get a better
sense of how it works. Some people probably prefer to keep the platform
as a black box but I like the flexibility to poke around a little bit if
I want to. Heroku on the other hand probably has a smoother command line
API to get stuff done but OpenShift isn’t too far behind. Another
appealing feature of OpenShift is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openshift.com/wiki/installing-openshift-origin-using-vagrant-and-puppet&quot;&gt;OpenShift
Origins&lt;/a&gt;
which appears to be a way to run a local copy of the OpenShift platform
for development. This could be a better way to get a local environment
close to what will be run in production than the Vagrant path that I
went for this project. Origins is also how you go about developing your
own “cartridges” (or “add-ons” in Heroku-speak) that you can use on the
platform and even share with others. Open source FTW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah, so that’s about it. I’m excited to see how (and if!) people use
this API. I’ve heard folks in the past talk about how something like
this would be helpful, so we’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on to the next project...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2013/09/09/philly-hoods.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2013/09/09/philly-hoods.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2013-2014 NBA Schedule</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I pushed to GitHub &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davewalk/2013-2014-nba-schedule&quot;&gt;a repo of the 2013-2014 NBA
Schedule&lt;/a&gt; by team in
JSON and CSV formats. The schedules were announced a few days earlier
and at the time they weren’t available anywhere to download. So I
created a few Python scripts that scraped the schedule from ESPN.com and
included information about where each game would be played, including
coordinates geocoded from the Google Maps API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not entirely sure why I did this! Well, I’m a total basketball nerd for
one. And I was annoyed that the data wasn’t available in a format that
it could easily be used. Since then basketball-reference.com and the
team sites on nba.com have included CSV downloads, but the formatting
differs from team-to-team and sometimes game times are in the local time
of the team, which is annoying. But my repo is standardized and would be
useful if you were making a NBA app. And &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davewalk/did-the-nba-team-win-last-night&quot;&gt;I happen to have
one&lt;/a&gt; that
is due for a re-write for the next season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storing shareable, scraped, static data (the three S’s!) on GitHub has
me thinking of what else I can do. What’s stopping me from updating
these schedules weekly with results once the season starts? What about
scraping ALL of the data for each game? Why not? Storage is free and
once I write the script it would be a snap to update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll have to think about this as the season approaches. In the meantime
hopefully someone comes across this repo out of the millions on GitHub
and finds it useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 14:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2013/08/13/2013-2014-nba-schedule.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2013/08/13/2013-2014-nba-schedule.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>ArcConsole</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I just released something that I’ve been working on recently:
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CityOfPhiladelphia/arc-console&quot; title=&quot;ArcConsole on GitHub&quot;&gt;ArcConsole&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://arc-console.s3-website-us-east-1.amazonaws.com/&quot; title=&quot;ArcConsole Demo&quot;&gt;Check out a
demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a simplified, intuitive API console for the ArcGIS REST API. It
uses awesome JavaScript libraries like Backbone, Backbone Forms, Chosen,
Bootstrap, Leaflet and Leaflet Draw to take some of the pain out of
querying data from the standard ArcGIS REST API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ArcGIS REST API is really powerful and the City of Philadelphia
(which I work for) is using it more in our open data efforts. We’ve got
some big time datasets on it like all of the Police Dept’s Part I crimes
since the beginning of 2006 and the Office of Property Assessments’
recent actual value initiative which set new values for almost every
property in the city. But, it can be frustrating for developers and
other users that are new to querying the API to get started. This
application attempts to make that on-boarding a bit easier by stripping
away some of the advanced features that we don’t see being used very
often. If the user needs those advanced features, like non-Web Mercator
spatial references, they can use the standard API console at any time.
But with this application the user doesn’t have to navigate to the
service and layer that they need, they just select the data set that
they want from the top drop-down and the rest of the parameters and the
application constructs the URL for them. There’s a static JSON file that
defines all of those endpoints and additional information like a
description and links to metadata can be included as well. Plus the
ability to draw the geometry that you want to query on instead of the
frustration of trying to the object string just right is a big step up
in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app’s still a work in progress and we’ll look to improve it over
time. With some server-side code, it could be extended into a full-blown
data extractor. There’s a lot still to do and you can check out the code
at the City of Philadelphia’s GitHub page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding a repo to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/CityOfPhiladelphia&quot; title=&quot;City of Philadelphia on GitHub&quot;&gt;official City of Philadelphia GitHub
page&lt;/a&gt;
was especially satisfying for me. The City of Philadelphia is on GitHub.
And I have some of my code in it. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 20:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2013/03/25/arcconsole.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2013/03/25/arcconsole.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PHL Crime Mapper Post Mortem</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little over a week since I released &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phlcrimemapper.com&quot;&gt;PHL Crime
Mapper&lt;/a&gt; and the response has been beyond
my wildest dreams. Here’s a few select quotes that made me proud:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philebrity.com/2013/01/14/theres-an-app-for-that-phl-crime-mapper/&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;…a handy
tool…&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philly.com/philly/news/breaking/New_website_gives_easiest_look_yet_at_Philly_crimes_by_neighborhood.html&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;…gives easiest look yet at crimes by
neighborhood&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://technicallyphilly.com/2013/01/15/phl-crime-mapper-app&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;…wins points for
simplicity…&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.phillymag.com/the_philly_post/2013/01/15/phl-crime-mapper-documents-citys-pain/&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;…nifty…&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newsworks.org/index.php/local//onward/49541-phl-crime-mapper-open-data-in-action&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;…handy interface for seeing where serious crimes are being
committed.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/greenperspectiv/status/291251453278949376&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;…crisp, easy to use…the simplicity and refinement of design is
excellent.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://philadelphia.cbslocal.com/2013/01/20/philadelphias-serious-crime-database-gets-makeover/&quot;&gt;I was even on the radio to talk about
it!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like seeing words like “handy” and “simplicity” because that’s
definitely what I was going for. The app strives to do one thing and
hopefully do it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a lot of feedback by email from community leaders and others
about how they found the app useful. I didn’t think of it before, but
this would be really helpful for community organizations and
neighborhood watch groups. I’ll have to think about ways to get the word
out to them in the future. Overall so far I’ve gotten a lot of feedback
that has solidified how I should move the development forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few things have been identified that need improvement. Some users had
issues with using the application in so far as drawing an area and
changing the date range. So tonight I added a “Draw” button to the black
box on the left that explains how to use the app. In the process I
actually decreased the height of that box by removing some copy from the
last sentence. So that’s good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that I have to work on is finding a date selector that
is easy to use. I really like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ghusse.github.com/jQRangeSlider/&quot;&gt;current
one&lt;/a&gt; but I’ve actually
witnessed myself a few people having trouble figuring out how it works.
I may find a different one (although I hate the calendar picker ones) or
at least put a hover over the slider that explains how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond that I’ve thought about some long term bigger additions that
could really make the app awesome. I also have to work on making sure
the codebase remains maintainable by using Backbone and maybe porting
the JavaScript to CoffeeScript. I’ve never used CoffeeScript before so
this would be a good way to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, some closing stats:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  30% of visits from mobile devices (including tablets). This number
was a bit surprising to me, but it shouldn’t be. There was a mobile
version but a healthy amount of these hits were on tablets, which
the app currently doesn’t support at all, which has been been
driving me crazy. I have to spend some time soon adding that
support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  The app was viewed in 46 states and 54 countries (whoa)!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Internet Explorer, Chrome and Safari split 70% of the traffic down
the middle, Firefox got 16% and a bucketful of other browsers got
the rest. Great to see Internet Explorer not in the lead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  Most toggled crime: Thefts. Which makes sense because there are so
many of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.philly.com/philly/news/breaking/New_website_gives_easiest_look_yet_at_Philly_crimes_by_neighborhood.html&quot;&gt;The Philly.com
article&lt;/a&gt;
accounted for about 63% of traffic, which is amazing. Interestingly
enough, a fifth of that came in through the mobile version of their
website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traffic has died down, so now it’s time to get back to work on
making the application better long term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2013/01/22/phl-crime-mapper-post-mortem.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2013/01/22/phl-crime-mapper-post-mortem.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>PHL Crime Mapper</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last month the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opendataphilly.org/opendata/resource/215/philadelphia-police-part-one-crime-incidents/&quot;&gt;City of Philadelphia released
data&lt;/a&gt;
on Part I (violent and serious property) crimes over the last six years.
Today I’m releasing a web application that uses that data to help folks
visualize these crimes in their area: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phlcrimemapper.com/&quot;&gt;PHL Crime
Mapper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a computer (non-mobile device), the application allows users to
select a time frame and draw a polygon around the area that they want to
view the crimes for. They can then toggle on/off different types of
crimes and can always change their data range or start over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a smartphone, users select either a 3, 5 or 10 block search area
(approximate) around their location. A tablet version is coming soon,
for now the app should be pretty worthless on iPads and the like. It was
important to me that there was a version of this app that worked on
smartphones and that it was just not the desktop version shrunken down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ultimate vision with this is to allow users to select the region
they want to know about and get a text or email alert weekly/monthly of
all the new crimes in that area. It’ll take some time to get there, but
I think the app really becomes useful at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I showed this to my friends over the weekend and one of them asked what
the objective is. I don’t really have one and I don’t know how people
will use it specifically. If they’re like me they’ll draw a polygon
around their house to view the recent crimes in their neighborhood.
Perhaps they’ll change the data range to see how crimes have changed
over time. To me the more you know the better, especially when it comes
to crime in your city and the Police Department thankfully releasing
this data lets it to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun working on this project and I’m pleased with the results for
now although there are some UX and loading time improvements that have
to be made. This was the first time that I got to work with
&lt;a href=&quot;http://leafletjs.com/&quot;&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; extensively, which is 100% awesome.
There were a few steps along the way where I thought that I would be
stuck because Leaflet has a smaller API than other client-side mapping
libraries, but it always had the perfect solution. Where Leaflet cannot
offer the functionality there are some great plugins that give you more,
including the awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jacobtoye/Leaflet.draw&quot;&gt;Leaflet
Draw&lt;/a&gt; that I am using here. I
may have to post again later about Leaflet. I have always been a fan of
the ‘Toner’ basemap from &lt;a href=&quot;http://maps.stamen.com/#toner/11/40.0020/-75.1180&quot;&gt;Stamen
Design&lt;/a&gt; and I finally
get to use it here. Overall the app is pretty fast once it’s initially
loaded, due to the fast Esri REST server that I’m calling for the data
(and geometry services) from and the markers being &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortawesome.github.com/Font-Awesome/&quot;&gt;Font
Awesome&lt;/a&gt; CSS sprites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope folks find this useful. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davewalk/phl-crime-mapper&quot;&gt;The code is up on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and pull requests
and new issues are welcome. It’ll be interesting to see how people use
it and I’m definitely open to making changes to make it more useful and
easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 07:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2013/01/14/phl-crime-mapper.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2013/01/14/phl-crime-mapper.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Know When To Go To Sleep</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been working on some side projects late into the night. If
I don’t have any commitments on a weekend I may stay up late working on
something and then sleep in the next day. Because I can, and it’s
awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also have to learn when it’s time to stop and &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/CseO1XRYs9I&quot;&gt;go the f**k to
sleep&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few nights ago I was working on one of these projects and got stuck on
one thing that wasn’t working even though I KNEW it should have been.
After struggling and trying to debug for 45 minutes, I gave up,
commented my battle in the code and went to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight I came back to that code and fixed my problem in less than a
minute. It made so much sense that I had a function call inside a loop
when it shouldn’t have been. With a clear head I caught the mistake
almost instantaneously, but a few nights before I toiled away forever to
no avail, cursing computers the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same thing just happened to me tonight: some parameter in a POST
request isn’t working and it’s not working even though it SHOULD BE. So
for now I’ll just go to sleep, dream of successful Ajax calls and come
back to it when the sun is up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 01:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2013/01/05/know-when-to-go-to-sleep.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2013/01/05/know-when-to-go-to-sleep.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>My 2013 New Year's resolutions</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s about that time again, isn’t it? For the past few years I’ve
tried to make and keep a list of New Year’s Resolutions. Problem is that
I’ve been changing my blogging platform so much that I can never link
back to review it a year later. Here’s to hoping this time is different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2012 was an awesome year for me, probably the best of my life. Here’s
what happened to me this year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Got married&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Got a great job that I really enjoy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Got to visit Paris, London and Brussels on our honeymoon. The first
time I’ve ever been outside of the United States&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Got my Master’s Degree (pending, but I’m done with classes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all of this was awesome, it’s all stuff that I &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt; was going to
happen and was already planning for in 2011. The challenge in 2013 is to
keep the momentum going after getting a lot of the big life things done.
So here’s what I’m shooting for in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Skills&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Learn HTML5 and the mobile web&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve started this already and
it’s clearly where the future of technology is going. A sub-goal
here is that every app I launch this year will look great on
smartphones, tablets and traditional desktops and a majority of them
will be designed for mobile first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Learn Android&lt;/strong&gt;. Yeah yeah, you can make more money in iOS, but
Android is going to continue to spread like a disease. Long term
this is a really good skill to have. Measurement: release at least
one app in the Google Play store. I’ve already got pretty solid
ideas for three, I just have to wrap my mind around how it all fits
together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Learn functional programming by the way of Scala&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve started
this already by beginning the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/course/progfun&quot;&gt;Coursera’s Scala
class&lt;/a&gt;. How awesome is it
to learn a programming language from its creator?! End goal: write
one substantial application in Scala.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Contribute to at least 3-5 open source projects&lt;/strong&gt;. This could be
creating and maintaining something that others find useful or having
pull requests accepted for other projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Attend five hackathons&lt;/strong&gt;. They’re a good way to stretch yourself,
code as a team under pressure and learn from others.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Learn D3.js&lt;/strong&gt;. Like really learn it, not just make a few bar
charts. Make something cool. At least five original, substantial
data visualizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Personal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Run 750 miles&lt;/strong&gt;. In 2010 I ran 1,000 miles, but I wasn’t able to
replicate that in 2011 due to injuries and just a lack of free time.
It’s not the energy that’s the problem but devoting 10+ hours a week
to running can be challenging. But 750 miles is a pretty healthy
number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Less distractions&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m constantly swamped in Google Reader like
it’s my job. I’ll have to make some subscription cuts to get my
unread count down and maybe sometimes “Mark all as read” button.
Also, cancel my magazine subscriptions (Wired and Fast Company).
There just isn’t enough time in the day to read everything I want to
read and I have to get used to that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Read 12 books&lt;/strong&gt;. In 2010 (man, I had free time in 2010) I read 24
books, which isn’t insane, just two books a month. While devoting
time to the above I think I can manage one book a month. Hopefully
more fiction than technology books to give myself a break.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Self Quantification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Get back onto Daytum&lt;/strong&gt;. In the second half of 2011 I sort of fell
off with Daytum which I was putting a lot of data into every day. In
2013 I resolve to be more dedicated to it, but not for everything
but only the important stuff. Also, I’ll work towards visualizing
the large dataset that I currently have about myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Write five days a week in 750 Words&lt;/strong&gt;. Writing in a journal helps
me reflect, especially at the beginning of end of a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Use at least one passive logging technique&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gurgeh/selfspy&quot;&gt;Selfspy&lt;/a&gt; looks interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s about it. Some of this kind of scares me, but I guess that’s
the point. I doubt that anyone will find this interesting, but I have to
put this list out publicly to motivate myself to get to work. I’ll check
back in the beginning of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 18:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2012/12/31/my-2013-new-years-resolutions.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2012/12/31/my-2013-new-years-resolutions.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Did The Cavs Win Last Night?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March 2014 Update: This app is currently broken due to Twitter&amp;#39;s API requiring authentication. I hope to bring it back and better than ever for the 2014-2015 season.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I finished up a little web app that I’ve been working on
over the last few weeks when I got a chance: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.didthecavswinlastnight.net&quot;&gt;Did The Cavs Win Last
Night?&lt;/a&gt; A while back I came
across &lt;a href=&quot;http://isthereagiantsgametoday.com/&quot;&gt;Is there a Giants game
today?&lt;/a&gt; and thought it was a great
idea in its simplicity. I’m definitely a fan of one-purpose single-page
apps because they can be really good at the very one thing that they are
trying to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I created something similar for the NBA that not only tells you when
the next game is, but tells you if your team won the night before. And
not only that, but it’ll give you fresh stories and videos about the
game. I envisioned folks waking up the day after a game to see how their
team did the night before. In the past I maybe went to NBA.com or
ESPN.com to get the score and some single wrap-up, but now with this app
it’s possible to get a bunch of viewpoints in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.didthecavswinlastnight.net/screenshot.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is entirely static. When a user accesses it it checks if there
was a game yesterday by calling a JSON file of the team’s schedule. If
there was, it’ll ask the Twitter account
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/SimpleNBAScores&quot;&gt;@SimpleNBAScores&lt;/a&gt; for the
score. It then pulls up stories from blogs and websites and videos on
Youtube about the game to give a more complete view of what happened and
what people are saying about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was fun to make and it gave me a chance to try out a few new things
like: media queries (pretty simple since this was one column), Canvas
(just one element but quadratic curves can be tricky) and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeoman.io&quot;&gt;Yeoman&lt;/a&gt;, which I can’t live without now. I also
have it hosted on S3, which is new to me but was pretty easy and working
well so far. Deploying through their web client is a pain, but I think
I’ll try to make a command line application that streamlines that a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While planning this project I did a lot of research into how I can get
sports scores on the client-side and basically there are none besides
that Twitter account. ESPN has an API, but the general public isn’t
given access to scores and you need a key anyway so it wouldn’t work on
the client. All other APIs for sports info are paid. There is one way
person that found a ESPN live score stream and he created RSS feeds to
scrap it, but I couldn’t make jQuery GET requests to it. So there’s
almost nothing, which is strange to me because sports scores are so
ubiquitous. You’d think that it would be in the NBA’s best interest to
put out a robust API, why not, but I guess there’s too much money at
stake. For now I’ll have to use the Twitter feed even though it’s using
a depreciated non-auth version of the API. If that goes down I’ll
probably have to create my own API that all version of Did The… can use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope people find it useful. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davewalk/did-the-nba-team-win-last-night&quot;&gt;The code is on
GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and
I’ve included instructions on how to setup it up for other teams.
Hopefully folks will fork it and deploy a version of their team!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<link>http://davewalk.net/2012/12/16/did-the-cavs-win-last-night.html</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://davewalk.net/2012/12/16/did-the-cavs-win-last-night.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>